So what I'd like you to do is to actually give this a shot,
practice around using the idea of a composable in your directory.
So basically, I kind of wanted to outline it a bit.
You'll create a Composables folder inside of your source directory.
Look inside of your app,
see what opportunities there might be to share some state or functionality.
Or if you don't have it obviously,
like I did earlier, just go and do so to practice it,
practice sharing those things.
So here, I said create a file called useState or useFunction.
Basically, I know in my case,
I call it countStore which is a lead-in for something else in the future.
But generally speaking,
when you're naming your Composables,
you do prefix it with that use.
So in that case, I should have probably named it like useCountStore for example.
Then otherwise, just try stuff out.
All right. So how that feel with the Composables?
Is that a bit weird to do?
I see a lot of people still typing,
so probably so tinkering away.
People in the chat,
if you had any issues with those Composables, please let me know.
So I'm just going ahead and walk through a simple example for
the solution and talk through
some theoretical things while we're at it.
So let's go ahead and switch over to sayLoveView.
So if we look at sayLoveView, what do we have?
Well, we have a couple things going on.
We have a user card here,
that's fine, user page.
Okay. We have some async stuff happening.
All right. Well, this is in the script setup.
So this actually might be a good one.
So let's say for instance then,
that we want the ability to display the users in more than one place.
Because the user page is a great place to list it,
but on the other hand,
there might be reasons to actually display it on like the homepage for instance.
So let's just abstract that away into a Composable.
So I'm going to go ahead and create a new folder here for Composables.
Then I'm going to create one and following the syntax now,
I'm going to call it useUserStore.js.
All we're going to do here is we're going to do
an import reactive from view.
Then we're going to export a const called userList.
Although actually, you know what I'm going to do?
I'm actually going to do,
because we're actually just exporting the single array,
I prefer usually to use ref when it's not an object.
So reactive is usually when I think of like a more complex object,
that's personally kind of where I lean towards.
So userList is a ref of an array.
That's all this is.
So now that we have this here,
we can go inside of user page and we can change this up basically to say,
okay, so I'm going to import from what?
We're going to go up one level,
go to Composables, go to useUserStore,
and then what we're looking for inside of here is the userList,
which is autocompleted right there.
So now we can technically delete this,
and then this means we can delete the reactive up here,
and then wherever userList is being called,
we will remove the state,
and then because we're in script setup,
remember that it's a ref,
so we need to unpack it with dot value.
Again, it's nice because the tooling has updated now,
so that it'll actually tell you that it's expected the dot value.
There was a time where the tooling hadn't caught up,
and so it was really easy to miss that on your own if you weren't paying attention.
So there we go, userList is now available.
We can save and everything should still look good.
Yeah, it looks good to me.
If we go to Home now,
let's actually show that we can do something similar.
So we'll go now over to the Home page.
So Home page, and I'll just use the script setup again up here,
and let me just actually copy that snippet over from up here.
So import, there we go, userList from that.
Import userList right here,
and again, once we've imported it,
the mental model shift that you have to think about here is that it is already available.
So we can go ahead and just do an LI in this case,
and then v4 userInUserList and then user.name.
I think that should work.
There we go. It's looking good.
Then to show you why this is incredibly powerful is that maybe in this specific context,
this is where I want to actually only show the first five.
So I don't need this to pollute the entire file.
What I can do is I can just import the computer property from view,
and just say const short userList is a computer property that
returns userList.value,
what was it, splice05, I think.
I think that returns it. Great.
Then we can do short userList here.
You'll notice, there we go.
Now we have this global piece of data that is shared in two files,
but we also have some very specific context on how we might want to manipulate
that data for that one component.
That in it of itself is, I think,
the power of the idea of the composition API in that you can really start to
compose things the way that makes sense to you.
So the other thing about View3,
which you're not going to cover at all,
but I did want to make a mention to it because those coming from View2 or
those looking at View3 docs might notice that
Mixins are a thing that also were particularly popular during the View2 days,
and Mixins what they basically allow you to do,
it was a way for you to share functionality and state using the options API.
Nowadays, I would say the fact that you have these
composables and reusable pieces of state and function that's easily
injectable in a very concise way,
these are basically superior to Mixins in every way, shape, and form.
It's really actually hard to argue for using Mixins over the composables.
So it is valuable to spend the time to get familiar with it,
try it out, and start figuring out where it lands in your comfort zone.
But as you can see here,
there's something really nice about being able to say,
oh, okay, yeah, I'm getting what the user list from where this use user store,
and then you just know where everything is,
everything's named correctly,
or if you need to update it because there's some name clashes,
everything is very declarative and explicit.
So yeah, so these are composables in a nutshell,
and that puts a wrap on the composition API section of all the things we're talking about.